# Joshua Villgren

### Game Producer

Mobile: +358 40 6537291

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshua-villgren/

**Email:** joshuavillgren@gmail.com **Location:** New Zealand/Remote

## About Me

Starting out as a hobbyist programmer, I began participating in game jams. After developing my practical skills, I led 7-10 people during 10 different 3-day game jams, through which I was recruited into the gaming industry as a Game Developer. My previous experience in leadership and attitude towards collaboration and organisation drove me into production.

## Skills and Tech

- 3+ years of Unity and Unreal development with a design and production focus.
- 4+ years working with GitHub/Plastic SCM/Perforce in software and game development environments.
- Experience setting up and using CI/CD pipelines with Unity Cloud Build, through GH Actions and CircleCI
- Familiar with game and software dev tools and processes (Agile, Scrum, Jira, etc.) as well as delivering to strict deadlines, sprint evaluation and data analysis for effective future planning.
- Incredibly high level of attention to detail and problem solving skills plus a strong background in data and tech.

## Work Experience

### **Game Developer**

### Rovio Entertainment | January 2023 - Current

- Working as a client game developer on the largest grossing game in the Rovio portfolio, Angry Birds Dream Blast
- Focus on meta, analytics, A/B test implementations and optimizations strategy.
- Sprint planning ownership and fortnightly review for client backlog features.
- Running learning presentation meetings, including planning, designing and delivering various development processes and tools such as advanced Unity and C#, and game design patterns.

### Junior Game Developer

### Rockodile Games | November 2021 - January 2023

- Production design for mobile and web based apps and games, including game and ad testing in Unity 2D/3D.
- · Game design and project planning for small scale local projects, one with a networking/multiplayer focus.
- Supporting and on-boarding interns during their study periods and guiding them through the game development lifecycle.
- Effective sprint maintenance for remote team with on prototyping projects.

## Additional Experience

### Game Jam team leader for Ludum Dare and GGJ events

### Programmer, Producer and Game Developer | April 2019 - Current

- Lead and produced for 10 code jams, taking a theme to an idea and launched a completed game successfully in 72 hours.
- Particular focus on production design, optimizations, bug fixing, and puzzle crafting.
- Code <u>here</u> and all recent game projects <u>here</u>.
- All projects in C#/Unity or JavaScript/HTML

## Qualifications and Education

#### Google

### Google Project Management: Professional Certificate

October 2023 - April 2024

### **Massey University**

### **Bachelor of Science | Computer Science and Mathematics**

July 2020 - June 2023

- Massey Scholar and graduating class Valedictorian
- A highly competent student with perfect grades in every course.
- Course marker and tutor for four computer science and mathematics courses.

## **Steps Drama Learning Development**

Leadership Skills Certificate - Leading in the Vodafone Way

February 2017